天外魔花
希尔大夫
Dr. Hill.
巴西特大夫
Dr. Bassett.
病人在哪里？
Where's the patient?
我真不想在这个时间
把你从床上拽起来
I hated
to drag you out of bed.
趁现在还来得及 放我走行吗？
Will you let me go
while there's still time?
你马上就会知道我为什么这么做了
You'll soon see why I did.
告诉这些白痴我没疯 好吗？
Will you tell
these fools I'm not crazy?
在一切都追悔莫及之前让他们听我说！
Make them listen to me
before it's too late!
我来听你说
I'll listen to you.
放开她
Let him go.
你是谁？
Who are you?
我是州立精神病院的希尔大夫
I'm Dr. Hill
from the state mental hospital.
我没疯！
I'm not insane!
放开他！
Let him go!
大夫 现在你必须认真听我说
Doctor,
now you must listen to me.
请你一定要理解我
You must understand me.
我也是名医生
我没疯
I am a doctor, too.
I am not insane.
- 我根本就没疯！
- 好吧 好吧
All right.
让我们坐下谈 医生
然后你告诉我到底发生了什么 好吗？
Suppose we sit down,
and you tell me what happened?
好 那是始于--
Well, it started...
对我来说
始于上个星期四...
for me,
it started last Thursday...
因为我的护士发来紧急通知
in response to an urgent
message from my nurse.
我从一个医学交流研讨大会上急忙赶回家
I'd hurried home
from a medical convention.
乍看之下
一切如常
At first glance,
everything looked the same.
但实际上并不是这样
It wasn't.
某种邪恶的气息已悄悄笼罩了这个小镇
Something evil had taken
possession of the town.
这两件
These two.
给
Here you are.
谢谢先生
请拿好
Thank you, sir.
There you are.
多谢
Thank you.
费希尔先生，早上好啊
Morning, Mr. Fisher.
大夫！
Doc!
嗨呀 莎莉
Hiya, Sally.
嗨 欢迎回家
真高兴你回来了
Hi. Welcome home.
I'm glad you're back.
米基和宝宝情况如何？
How's Mickey and the baby?
他们挺好的 可是看起来似乎
圣米拉城里的每个人都需要看医生
Fine, but everybody else
in Santa Mira needs a doctor.
你的诊室都被病人塞满了
You've got an office
full of patients.
噢 不要啊
我第一天回来就这样？
Oh, no.
On my first day back?
他们之中有些人已经等了你两星期了
Some of them have
been waiting for two weeks.
为什么不让他们去找珀西
或者卡迈克尔大夫呢？我跟你说过的
Why didn't you send them
to Pursey or Carmichael?
可他们大多都不愿意
他们只想见你
Most of 'em wouldn't go.
They want to see you.
哦？
Oh?
他们有什么症状？
What's the matter with them?
他们就是不说
They wouldn't say.
你知道通常病人们都迫不及待
要描述自己的病症
Usually people can't talk enough
about what's ailing them.
比如说
沃利·埃伯哈德来了两次...
For instance,
Wally Eberhard was in twice...
而且打过三次电话
但他就是不谈自己有什么症状
and called three times,
but he wouldn't say about what.
有点意思
That's funny.
没有一个人愿意说--
从贝基·德里斯科尔...
Nobody would talk...
from Becky Driscoll...
到那个胖交警萨姆·雅纳切克
down to that fat
traffic cop Sam Janzek.
贝基·德里斯科尔？
我以为她在英国呢
Becky Driscoll?
I thought she was in England.
几天前她就回来了
而且她点名要见你
She got back a few days ago,
and she wanted to see you.
还对她有兴趣？
Are you still interested?
我对已婚妇女的兴趣仅限于
严谨的职业范围内...
My interest in married women
is strictly professional...
否则怎能长期抗拒你的诱惑
or yours would have been
a lost cause long ago.
- 研讨会怎么样？
- 棒极了
- How was the convention?
- Wonderful.
我宣读我的论文时
他们简直嫉妒得泪流满面
They wept with envy
when I read my paper.
回来！
MRS. GRIMALDl: Come back here!
吉米！
Jimmy!
怎么了
格里马尔迪太太？
What's the matter,
Mrs. Grimaldi?
没什么 他就是不愿意上学！
It's nothing. He just don't
want to go to school.
我要是你的话
就会去找她的老师谈谈
If I were you, I'd have
a talk with his teacher.
等有时间了我就去
MRS. GRIMALDl:
I will when I get time.
发生什么了
乔生病了吗？
What's the matter?
Has Joe been sick?
不 我们只是不再经营这个市场了
MRS. GRIMALDl: No.
We gave the stand up.
- 需要太多劳动力
- 哦
- Too much work.
- Oh.
那孩子的惊慌失措当时就应该让我明白...
The boy's
panic should have told me...
他所恐惧的绝不仅仅是上学...
it was more than school
he was afraid of...
还有那堆满垃圾的 倒闭了的菜市场...
and that littered,
closed-up vegetable stand...
也许也在暗示着些什么
should have
told me something, too.
我最后一次看见它的时候
还是在不到一个月之前...
When I last saw it,
less than a month ago...
那时它还是这条大路上
最整洁最繁忙的一个市场
it was the cleanest
and busiest stand on the road.
真是奇怪
That's strange.
她也来找过你--
就在上周五
She was in to see you, too...
last Friday.
我曾尝试说服她去找珀西大夫
但她不愿意
I tried to get her to see
Doc Pursey, but she wouldn't.
她说只有你才能帮助她
She said only you
could help her.
好吧 不管她有什么毛病...
Whatever it was...
我想应该都不会很严重
it couldn't have been
too serious, I guess.
一例轻微脑震荡 两例普通感冒...
One minor concussion,
two cases of the common cold...
还有六个已取消的预约
and six canceled appointments.
看来你急急忙忙把我拽回来
也并没有什么事嘛
Looks like you rushed me here
for nothing.
我不明白...
他们都迫不及待要见你啊
I don't understand it.
They couldn't wait to see you.
不过今天下午你的日程也会排得满满的
But you're still booked up solid
for the afternoon.
我打赌他们不会来
看那里 是沃利·埃伯哈德...
I bet they don't show.
Look, there's Wally Eberhard...
正在跟路人推销保险呢
talking somebody
into buying some insurance.
他一点问题也没有嘛
There's nothing wrong with him.
比尔·比特纳正要带他的小秘去吃午饭
Bill Bitner's taking
his secretary to lunch.
啊 说到午饭...
And speaking of lunch...
能否跟来找我的任何人说 我去用餐了？
will you tell whoever that is
that I'm out having mine?
本耐尔大夫在吗？
Is Dr. Bennell in?
是的 他在
Yes, he's here.
你认为他有空接待我吗？
Do you suppose
he has time to see me?
如果他没出什么毛病的话
If he hasn't,
something's wrong with him.
进去吧
Go right in.
贝基
Becky.
快五年了
Almost five years.
回家的感觉真好
It's wonderful to be home again.
我离开得太久了...
I've been away so long...
回到老家却觉得自己像个外乡人
I feel almost like a stranger
in my own country.
我没有预约就来了 但愿你别介意
Hope you don't mind my coming
without an appointment.
才不会
想做点什么？
Not at all.
What'll you have?
这周我们做推广促销的是阑尾切除术
We're pushing appendectomies
this week.
噢 米尔斯
Oh, Miles.
我不知道 或许我老是胡闹乱开玩笑
I don't know,
maybe I clown around too much.
用不了多久 我的病人们...
Pretty soon, my patients...
就会连我给他们开的阿司匹林都不敢信任了
won't trust me
to prescribe aspirin for them.
说真的 是有什么问题？
Seriously, what's the trouble?
是我表妹
It's my cousin.
威尔玛？
她怎么了？
Wilma?
What's the matter with her?
她出现了些 呃...
She has a...
我猜你们称之为“幻觉”
I guess you'd call it
a delusion.
你认识他叔叔吧？
艾拉叔叔？
You know her uncle?
Uncle Ira?
当然 我是他的大夫
Sure. I'm his doctor.
现在她自己认为他不是她的叔叔
She's got herself
thinking he isn't her uncle.
你指的是什么？
他们实际上没有血缘关系？
How do you mean?
That they're not really related?
她觉得他是个冒充的傀儡一类的...
She thinks
he's an impostor or something...
...某种只是外表看起来是艾拉叔叔的东西
someone who only looks like Ira.
你见过他了吧？
Have you seen him?
我就是刚从他那过来的
I just came from there.
他到底是不是艾拉叔叔呢？
Is he Uncle Ira,
or isn't he Uncle Ira?
当然是啦
Of course he is.
我跟威尔玛强调过了 可是没有用
I told Wilma that,
but it was no use.
拜托 你有空的话能否顺便过去和她聊聊？
Please, would you stop by
and have a talk with her?
莎莉说我整个下午的日程都排满了...
Sally says I'm booked up
for the afternoon...
不过你为什么不让她过来找我呢
but why don't you ask her
to come in and see me?
我试试吧
I'll try.
呃 共进午餐如何？
How about some lunch?
不行 我一会要去店里见爸爸
I can't.
I'm meeting Dad at the store.
你是什么时候回来的
When did you get back?
两个月前从伦敦回来的
I came back from London
two months ago.
之前我一直是在里诺
【里诺：美国有名的“离婚城市”
位于内华达州西部】
I've been in Reno.
里诺？
Reno?
里诺
Reno.
爸爸告诉过我你也曾待在那里
Dad tells me
you were there, too.
五个月前吧
Five months ago.
哦 真遗憾
Oh, I'm sorry.
我有同感
So was I.
我曾希望我们能在那相遇
I wanted it to work.
好吧 我想现在我们终于上了同一条船
I guess that makes us
lodge brothers now.
是的
Yes.
除了我付租你收租的区别以外
Except I'm paying dues
while you collect them.
哈哈哈 米尔斯
Ha ha ha! Miles.
- 哈喽 大夫
- 你好吗？
- Hello, doc.
- How are you?
萨姆！
Sam!
又在贴条了哈？
At it again, eh?
我的护士告诉我你上周来过诊室...
My nurse tells me
you were in last week...
而且迫切要与我会面
and wanted very much
to see me.
没那么严重的啦
It wasn't anything important.
他跟我们一起上过学吗？
Didn't he go to college with us?
大二的时候为了结婚退学了...
Quit his second year
to get married...
就像我曾希望咱俩去做的那样
like I wanted us to do.
应该感到庆幸的是我没当真
Just be thankful
I didn't take you seriously.
不感到庆幸？
You be thankful.
我发现要成为一名医生的妻子...
I found out
that a doctor's wife...
需要有对爱因斯坦的理解和包容...
needs the understanding
of an Einstein...
还要有圣人的耐心
and patience of a saint.
那爱情呢？
And love?
我怎么知道
I wouldn't know about that.
我不过是个普通医师而已
I'm just a general practitioner.
爱情这玩意还是留给啥专家们去搞定吧
Love is handled
by the specialists.
好吧 我该走了
Here's where I leave you.
你知道吗？
You know something?
这该是你最后一次离开我身边
This is where you left me
the last time.
嗨 约翰尼
Hiya, Johnny.
莎莉 我该走了
Sally, I'm off.
告诉接线生我会在自己家里
Tell the answering service
I'll be at home.
晚安 大夫
Good night, doc.
我不要进去...
I'm not going in there!
别胡闹了！
MRS. GRIMALDl:
Stop all this nonsense.
嘿 嘿 放松点
Hey! Take it easy!
这不是小吉米 格里马尔迪吗？
Isn't this Jimmy Grimaldi?
是的 大夫
我能跟你谈谈吗？
MRS. GRIMALDl: Yes, Doctor.
Can I talk to you a moment?
当然 知道吗
今早我差点开车撞到你
Sure. I almost
ran you down this morning.
过马路的时候可要加倍小心哦
You got to be careful
when you run out in the road.
来
Come on.
过来
MRS. GRIMALDl: Come on.
嘿！嘿！嘿！
Hey! Hey! Hey!
嘿！别着急
Hey! Slow down now.
去上学也不是那么糟糕的呀
School isn't as bad as all that.
上学不是让他变成这样的原因
MRS. GRIMALDl:
School isn't what upsets him.
是我儿媳
It's my daughter-in-law.
他不知怎么产生的这个疯念头
觉得她不是他妈妈
He's got the crazy idea
she isn't his mother.
她不是！她就不是！
She isn't! She isn't!
别让她抓住我！
Don't let her get me!
没人会来抓你的 吉米
Nobody's going
to get you, Jimmy.
这个症状持续多久了？
How long has this been going on?
一个小时前 我在地窖发现他在那里藏着
MRS. GRIMALDl: An hour ago,
I found him in the cellar.
他一言不发 直到我开始给他妈妈打电话
He wouldn't say anything until
I started to phone his mother.
这时他告诉我安娜不是他妈妈
That's when he said Anna
wasn't his mother.
你能暂时让他在你那里呆一两天吗？
Could you keep him
with you for a day or so?
这个药给他每四小时吃一次
Give him one of these every
four hours during the day.
明天给我打个电话 告诉我他情况如何
Call me tomorrow and let me know
how he's feeling.
好的 大夫 谢谢你
MRS. GRIMALDl:
Yes, Doctor, thank you.
别让她抓住我！
Don't let her get me!
没人会来抓你的
Nobody's going to get you.
好吧 吉米
All right, Jimmy.
张开嘴
Open your mouth.
闭上眼睛
Shut your eyes.
以诗人之名...
In the words of the poet...
我给你吃令人充满智慧的神奇药丸
I'll give you something
to make you wise.
真是个好孩子 吉米
That's a good boy, Jimmy.
我绝不要回家
I'm not going home ever.
你会暂时留在奶奶家的
给他妈妈打个电话...
You're staying at your
grandmother's. Call his mother.
她不是我妈妈！
She's not my mother!
好吧好吧 你们先回去
一切都会没事的
All right. Run along.
Everything's going to be OK.
做个乖孩子哦
You be a good boy now.
晚安 大夫
MRS. GRIMALDl:
Good night, Doctor.
晚安
Good night.
我改变主意了
我先不直接回家去
I've changed my mind.
I'm not going directly home.
顺路去看看威尔玛·伦茨的情况
I'm going to stop off
and see Wilma Lentz.
我需要给这孩子的母亲打个电话？
Should I call the boy's mother?
是的 告诉她发生了什么...
Yes.
Tell her what happened...
并且告诉她我建议最好先让孩子...
and that I suggested
the boy spend the night...
住在他奶奶家
at his grandmother's house.
你好 米尔斯
Hello, Miles.
见到你真好 威尔玛 贝基
Nice to see you, Wilma.
Becky.
直奔主题吧
Let's have it.
你刚才跟他聊过了 有什么感想？
You talked to him.
What do you think?
就是他 没错啊
It's him.
他就是你的艾拉叔叔，一切正常
He's your Uncle Ira, all right.
他才不是
He is not.
他有什么变化吗？
How is he different?
就是这样子
That's just it.
根本就没有肉眼能发现的区别
There is no difference
you can actually see.
他的外表 说话和行事风格 以及记忆...
He looks, sounds, acts,
and remembers...
都跟艾拉叔叔一样
like Uncle Ira.
那他就是你的艾拉叔叔啊
Then he is your Uncle Ira.
你不明白吗？
不管你有什么样的感觉 他就是
You see that?
No matter how you feel, he is.
但他不是
有哪里不对劲 好像缺失了什么
But he isn't.
There's something missing.
当我还小的时候 他对我视如己出
He's been a father to me
since I was a baby.
每当他跟我说话的时候...
Always when he talked to me...
他的眼神里有些很特别的东西
there was a special look
in his eye.
现在这样的眼神不见了
That look's gone.
那记忆方面如何？
肯定有某些特别的东西...
What about memories?
There must be certain things...
是只有你们两个人知道的
that only you and he
would know about.
有的
There are.
我跟他聊过这些
他全部都记得...
I've talked to him about them.
He remembers them all...
哪怕是最微小的细节
就像艾拉叔叔会记得的一样
down to the last small detail,
just like Uncle Ira would.
但是 米尔斯...
But, Miles...
他没有情感
there's no emotion.
毫无！
None!
只有假装出来的情感
Just the pretense of it.
语言 姿势 声调...
The words, gesture,
the tone of voice...
任何的一切都跟原来没有区别
除了感情
everything else is the same,
but not the feeling.
不管他有没有记忆
他都不是我的艾拉叔叔
Memories or not,
he isn't my Uncle Ira.
威尔玛 我是站在你这边的
Wilma, I'm on your side.
我的事业是帮助需要帮助的人...
My business
is people in trouble...
我会找到可以帮你的方法
and I'm going to find
a way to help you.
没有人可能扮成你的艾拉叔叔...
No one could possibly
impersonate your Uncle Ira...
并还能让你和艾莱达伯母 甚至我...
without you
or your Aunt Eleda or even me...
都找不出千万个破绽的
seeing a million
little differences.
我希望你能认识到这一点
I want you to realize that.
好好想想
然后你就会明白...
Think about it,
and then you'll know...
是你自己的问题
that the trouble is inside you.
威尔玛 你在哪？
Wilma, where are you?
在草坪上
Out on the lawn.
什么也别跟她说
Say nothing to her.
哎呀 米尔斯
我都不知道你来了
Why, Miles,
I didn't know you were here.
欢迎回来
Welcome home.
你好 伦茨太太
Hello, Mrs. Lentz.
你们邀请米尔斯留下共进晚餐了吗？
Did you ask Miles
to stay for dinner?
今晚不行
Can't tonight.
我今天做了蛋奶糕
I'm making spoon bread.
拜托 可别诱惑我
Please, don't tempt me.
下次有机会吧
Maybe next time.
威尔玛 我的眼镜在哪儿？
Wilma, where are my glasses?
我想大概在壁炉台上
I think
they're on the mantelpiece.
我跟你一起去拿
I'll go with you.
我是发疯了吗？
Am I going crazy?
别可怜我 我必须知道
Don't spare me.
I've got to know.
不 你没有疯
即使是当今...
No, you're not.
Even these days...
发疯也不是一件如你想象中
那般容易的事情啊
it isn't as easy to go crazy
as you might think.
不过你不用过于迫切...
But you don't have to be
losing your mind...
去寻求精神科的治疗
to need psychiatric help.
我希望你能见见我的一个医生朋友
I'd like you to see
a doctor friend of mine.
- 心理医生吗？
- 丹·考夫曼
- A psychiatrist?
- Dan Kauffman.
明天我会帮你预约
I'll make an appointment
for you tomorrow.
好吧
All right.
可那纯属浪费时间
我什么毛病也没有
But it's a waste of time.
There's nothing wrong with me.
先到此为止吧 不然他会起疑的
Better break this up,
or he'll start wondering.
起疑什么？
Wondering what?
不乱想的话 你的来访对我帮助很大...
If I don't suspect.
You've been a big help...
我不想你们任何人为我担心
and I don't want either of you
to worry about me.
我会好好的
I'll be all right.
你当然会啦
Sure you will.
你要留在这吗 贝基？
还是我送你回家？
Staying here, Becky?
Or may I drive you home?
想让我留下吗？
Would you like me to stay?
当然不了
晚安
Of course not.
Good night.
晚安
贝基回来了真好啊？孩子
Nice having Becky
back again, eh, boy?
可说呢
Sure is.
我的脑海深处...
In the back of my mind...
响起了警钟
a warning bell was ringing.
那些迫不及待需要见我的病人们...
Sick people
who couldn't wait to see me...
一夜之间全部恢复正常：
then suddenly
were perfectly all right.
一个哭喊着他妈妈不再是他的妈妈的孩子
A boy claiming
his mother wasn't his mother.
一个宣称她的叔叔不再是她的叔叔的女人
A woman claiming her uncle
wasn't her uncle.
但当时我并没有听警钟的召唤
But I didn't listen.
很明显 孩子的妈妈还是他妈妈
Obviously, the boy's mother
was his mother.
我见过她了
而艾拉叔叔还是艾拉叔叔
I had seen her.
And Uncle Ira was Uncle Ira.
当我与他交谈过以后 这简直毫无疑问
There was no doubt of that
after I talked to him.
米尔斯 他确实是艾拉叔叔？
Miles, he is Ira?
当然 你的意思是？
Of course he is.
What do you mean?
只是威尔玛实在是太坚定了
It's just Wilma's so positive.
她会好起来吗？
Will she be all right?
我想会的
I think so.
从学历上来看 我是一个医生...
I'm a doctor,
according to my diploma...
但我真的看不出威尔玛有什么毛病
but I don't really know
what Wilma's trouble is.
我可以讲一些精神科的术语来糊弄人...
I could start talking
psychiatrical jargon...
不过那就越界了
这是丹·考夫曼的领域
but it's out of my line
and in Dan Kauffman's.
真希望你不用回家吃晚饭
I wish you didn't have
to go home for dinner.
不用的 爸爸跟朋友出去吃饭了
I don't.
Dad's eating out with a friend.
7点我来接你
I could pick you up
at 7:00.
嗯...
Well...
现在是夏天 而且会是满月哦
It's summer,
and the moon is full.
“我知道一处浅滩...”
"I know a bank...
“铺满了狂野的百里香”
"where the wild thyme grows. "
你真是一点都没变
You haven't changed a bit.
哇！哇！注意点！
Whup! Whoa! Watch out!
抱歉
Sorry.
嘿 米尔斯
你什么时候回来的？
Hey, Miles,
when did you get back?
今早
丹尼 你好吗？
This morning.
How are you, Danny?
这位是德里斯科尔小姐
This is Miss Driscoll.
这是考夫曼先生--
我们的一位 也是唯一的一位精神科专家
Dr. Kauffman...
our one and only psychiatrist.
注意自己的言行
埃德，还记得贝基吗？
Watch out what you say.
Ed, you remember Becky.
必须的
她出生时是我接生的
I should.
I brought her into the world.
你可给大家做了一件大好事
You did us all a favor.
这下我就不用专门给你打电话了
This saves me a phone call.
我这有一个小孩和一位女性 需要一名巫医
I've got a kid and a woman
who need a witch doctor.
孩子说爸爸不是爸爸了...
Boy says his father
isn't his father...
然后女人说姐妹不是姐妹了？
and the woman says her sister
isn't her sister?
还真差不多
That's pretty close.
我知道你一直在研究催眠术...
I knew you'd been
studying hypnosis...
不过你什么时候学会读心术啦？
but when did you start
reading minds?
他不需要使用读心术
He doesn't have to read them.
自从这种情况开始以来
我已经给他那里送去了一打多的病人了
I've sent him a dozen patients
since it started.
是什么？
怎么回事？
What is it?
What's going on?
我不知道
一种奇怪的神经性现象...
I don't know.
A strange neurosis...
显然极具蔓延性--
像是一场可传染的集体性癔病
evidently contagious...
an epidemic of mass hysteria.
两周之后
席卷了整个小镇
In two weeks,
it's spread all over town.
是什么引起的？
What causes it?
过于操心世界局势所导致的吧 或许
Worry about
what's going on in the world.
明天给威尔玛·伦茨安排一下吧好吗？
Make room
for Wilma Lentz tomorrow.
让她2点左右过来
晚安
Send her in around 2:00.
Good night.
再会 丹尼
So long, Danny.
这真是我听到过最诡异的事
This is the oddest thing
I ever heard of.
但愿我们别染上这毛病
Let's hope we don't catch it.
我绝不愿某天早上醒来...
I'd hate to wake up
some morning...
发现身边的你不再是你
and find out you weren't you.
我可不再是那时候被你的浪漫
哄得晕头转向的高中女生了
I'm not the high-school
kid you used to romance.
你怎么分辨呢？
How could you tell?
真的想知道？
You really want to know?
嗯哼
Mm-hmm.
唔~~~
你是贝基·德里斯科尔没错
Mmm.
You're Becky Driscoll.
嘿 圣米拉真是越来越蒸蒸日上了
Hey, Santa Mira's looking up.
从你回来后才开始的
Has ever since you got back.
你平时对病人也是这种态度吗 大夫？
（bedside manner 双关语）
Is this an example
of your bedside manner, Doctor?
不 女士 那件事可要等一会儿
（贝基意指病床边 米尔斯指床上）
No, ma'am.
That comes later.
晚上好 大夫
Good evening, Doctor.
人都到哪儿去了？
What happened
to the crowd tonight?
我不知道
这种情况已经持续好几周了
I don't know.
It's been this way for weeks.
好吧 至少我们不用等桌位了
At least we don't
have to wait for a table.
你挑吧 坐这里 还是那边
Take your pick.
Here or here.
这边吧 我想
怎么样？
Here, I think.
Shall we?
嗯
Mm-hmm.
乐队到哪里去了？
Where's the band?
生意不景气
所以我只好把他们打发走了
Business slumped,
so I had to let them go.
不过那边还有自动唱机
There's the jukebox, though.
跳支舞吧？
Shall we dance?
希望你还没有把酒保打发走
I hope you didn't
let the bartender go.
我就是酒保
喝马提尼？
I'm the bartender.
Martinis?
两杯 烈的
Two. Dry.
要很烈
Very dry.
米尔斯 我不在意考夫曼医生说了些什么
Miles, I don't care
what Dr. Kauffman says.
我只是很担心
I'm worried.
你现在可是在...
You are in the capable hands...
你最得力的私人医师手里
of your personal physician.
噢 大夫
Oh, Doctor.
啊 我们的夜生活...
Ah, there's our evening.
抱歉
Sorry.
谢谢
Thanks.
本耐尔大夫
Dr. Bennell.
杰克·拜里塞克想要你现在立刻赶到他家去
Jack Belicec wants you
to come to his house right away.
他说是紧急情况
He says it's urgent.
谢谢
Thank you.
还是把酒收起来吧
Better hold those drinks.
急诊
Emergency.
还好至少他们在我们开始
共进晚餐前打来了电话
At least they called
before we ordered dinner.
你饿不饿？
How hungry are you?
我可以等
I can wait.
可能会久一些
It may be a while.
我和你一起去
I'll go with you.
对不起 我们一会再回来
Sorry.
We'll be back later.
杰克在那里
There's Jack.
你好 杰克 怎么了？
泰迪生病了？
What's the matter?
Teddy sick?
没有
No.
谢天谢地 我以为你来不了了
Thank heaven.
I thought you'd never arrive.
那是谁病了？
Then who is sick?
没人生病
Nobody.
那你为什么要把我从餐桌前揪过来？
Then why'd you
drag me away from my dinner?
你不会相信的 米尔斯
直到你自己亲眼目睹
You won't believe it
until you see it.
你好 贝基
Hello, Becky.
- 你好 贝基
- 嗨 泰迪
- Hello, Becky.
- Hi, Teddy.
能否暂时先把你的医生身份抛在脑后？
Could you forget
you're a doctor a while?
为何？
Why?
我不想你马上去叫警察
I don't want you
calling the police.
别整得像个文艺青年
到底怎么了？
Quit acting like a writer.
没准你能告诉我发生了什么
你可是医生
Maybe you can tell me.
You're the doctor.
米尔斯 把台球桌上面的灯打开
Miles, put the light on
over the pool table.
继续 拉开它
Go on. Pull it down.
你有什么结论？
What do you make of it?
这是谁？
Who is he?
我毫无头绪
I have no idea.
它的脸 米尔斯
模糊不清
Its face, Miles.
It's vague.
第一印象
就好像硬币上印着的头像一样
Like the first impression
that's stamped on a coin.
它还未完成
It isn't finished.
没错
You're right.
只有大概的容貌
但是没有细节...
All the features
but no details...
没有特征 没有线条
no character, no lines.
它不是具人类尸体
It's no dead man.
你家有拓印台吗？
Have you got
an ink pad around the house?
桌子上有一个
干嘛用？
There's one in the desk.
Why?
我想提取一下这具躯体的指纹
I want to take
the corpse's fingerprints.
这肯定是具死尸 不然还能是什么？
Of course
it's a dead man.
我不知道 但是我有一种感觉...
I don't know,
but I've got a feeling that...
我知道这听起来很疯狂
但是如果我做一下尸体解剖的话...
I know this sounds crazy,
but if I should do an autopsy...
我想每个器官大概都是完美无损的...
I think I'd find every organ
in perfect condition...
完美无缺
就像这具躯体外表看起来那样...
as perfect
as the body is externally...
躯体状况良好
everything in working order.
准备就绪 把那个拿过来
All set to go. Hold that down.
没有指纹...
These are blank.
像是在等待脸部完成...
Waiting for the final
finished face...
...以后才会变出来
to be stamped onto it.
但 是谁的脸？
But whose face?
告诉我
Tell me that.
我想我们可以先喝一杯
We could all use a drink.
喝波本可以吗？
Bourbon all right?
好的
Fine.
我不喝 谢谢
Not for me, thanks.
米尔斯 告诉我 是谁的脸？
Miles, answer me.
Whose face?
我连一点点头绪都没有...
I haven't the slightest idea...
你有吗？
have you?
你...你觉得那玩意有多高？
How tall would you say
that thing is?
哦 大概5英尺10英寸（1米78）左右
Oh, 5'10", thereabouts.
有多重？
How much does it weigh?
比较瘦小
大概140磅
It's pretty thin.
Maybe 140 pounds.
杰克身高5英尺10英寸
体重140磅
Jack's 5'10"
and weighs 140 pounds.
泰迪 能不能别再一派胡言了！
Teddy, will you stop
talking nonsense?
亲爱的 抱歉
但是我没有乱讲
I'm sorry, darling,
but it isn't nonsense.
贝基 你不认为我在瞎说 是不是？
Becky, you don't think
it's nonsense, do you?
当然是瞎说啦
Of course it is.
杰克就在这里 站在你面前啊
Jack's standing here
in front of you.
我当然站在这了 而且正在血流成河
Of course I am,
bleeding to death.
劳驾
Excuse me.
知道吗？
You know what?
我很遗憾 你保住了性命
I'm afraid you may live.
好了 这样就没事了
Here, this should fix it.
米尔斯 我们要不要报警...
Miles,
shouldn't we call the police...
然后让他们把这具死尸搬走？
and have them take
that dead body out of here?
我很抱歉
这并不是一具尸体
I'm afraid
it isn't just a dead body.
多谢
Thanks.
我很好奇...
I wonder if...
什么？
What?
我好奇
这些事情之间是否有什么关联
I wonder
if there's any connection.
你指的是什么？
What do you mean?
有一些奇怪的事情正在
圣米拉缓缓拉开序幕
There's something
strange afoot in Santa Mira.
考夫曼医生管它叫
传染性的集体歇斯底里性癔病
Dr. Kauffman calls it
an epidemic of mass hysteria.
贝基的表妹就得了这个病
Becky's cousin's got it,
for one.
她认为她的叔叔和婶婶...
She thinks that her uncle
and her aunt...
不再是她的叔叔和婶婶
aren't her uncle and her aunt.
已经出现多例这样的幻想症了
There's several cases
of such delusion.
这个东西还没有完全化身为你的样子...
This isn't you yet...
但从结构上来说显然是及其相近了
but there is
a structural likeness.
真不可思议
It's fantastic.
这玩意出现在这里一定有什么原因
There must be some reason
this is here.
要不要坐下来...
Would you be willing
to sit up...
然后等着瞧你这位“朋友”
接下来会发生什么？
and see what your friend's
next move is?
如果到早上还没有什么动静
我们就报警
If nothing happens by morning,
call the police.
如果发生了些什么呢...
If something happens...
就给我打电话 好吗？
call me, will you?
你知道我会的
You know I will.
晚安 放松点
Good night.
Take it easy.
好的
Sure.
不会发生什么的
Nothing will happen.
晚安 贝基
Good night, Becky.
如果真的发生了什么...
If it does...
一定会是个令人毛骨悚然的
恐怖小说的好素材
it'll make a charming,
bloodcurdling mystery story.
我很谨慎地没有让贝基察觉出来...
I was careful
not to let Becky know...
但当时我真的被吓坏了
but I was really scared.
丹·考夫曼对于
镇上发生的怪事的解释...
Dan Kauffman's explanation
of what was wrong in town...
歇斯底里的集体性癔病...
mass hysteria...
解释不了为什么杰克的台球桌上
会有那样一具躯体
couldn't explain away that body
on Jack's billiard table.
进来吧
我先去开灯
Come in
while I turn the lights on.
你真是个奔放的少妇...
You're a forward wench...
为了强吻我 把我拉到这漆黑的走廊里来
dragging me into a dark hallway
to be kissed.
我把你拉到漆黑的走廊里...
I'm dragging you
into a dark hallway...
是因为今晚我怕黑
because I'm scared of the dark
tonight.
我最好留下来把你裹在怀里
I'd better stay
and tuck you in.
那样就太疯狂了
That way lies madness.
疯狂又怎么啦？
What's wrong with madness?
就是太疯了
晚安
Madness.
Now good night.
想来你俩也该到家了
It's about time
you two got home.
爸 这么晚你在地下室干什么？
Dad, what are you doing
in the basement this late?
整理杂物
Working in my shop.
想来点酒吗 大夫？
Want a nightcap, doc?
不 谢了
时间不早了
No, thanks.
It's kind of late.
改天奉陪
晚安
I'll take a rain check.
Good night.
晚安
晚安 米尔斯
Good night, Miles.
啊！
Aaah!
看呐 杰克！
Look, Jack!
它变成你了！是你！
It's you! It's you!
不 不！
千万不要靠近它！
No, no!
You mustn't go near it!
快离开这里！拜托！
Get out of here! Please!
求你！
Please!
米尔斯！
Miles!
发生什么了 杰克？
What happened, Jack?
泰迪说屋里的那个生物变成了我...
Teddy says the thing
in our place is me...
连受伤的割伤都出现了
right down
to the cut on my hand.
我赶紧跑去看它
I didn't wait to look.
它活过来了！是活的！
It's alive! It's alive!
那受伤的伤口在流血！
The hand was cut and bleeding!
位置也挪动了！
And the position
of the body had changed!
来 这里 吃了这个
Here, here. Take this.
我这就给丹尼·考夫曼打电话
I'll call Danny Kauffman.
你好！
Hello?
你好 丹尼？
Hello, Danny?
是的！
Yeah?
有情况发生了
我必须立刻见你
Something's happened.
I've got to see you.
你能迅速赶过来吗？
Will you get over here fast?
非常重要的事情
It's important.
哦...好的
Oh... OK.
他在路上了
He's on his way.
我去弄点咖啡就过来
I'll make some coffee
and be right with you.
好主意 米尔斯
谢了
Good deal, Miles.
Thanks.
对了 贝基怎么样？
她没事吧？
What about Becky?
Do you think she's all right?
爸 这么晚你在地下室做什么？
Dad, what are you
doing in the basement this late?
整理杂物
Working in my shop.
我不知道当时是什么情况...
I don't know what it was...
大概是种预感...
call it a premonition...
忽然间 我感受到了贝基身边的危险气息
but suddenly, I had the feeling
that Becky was in danger.
我尽我所能地迅速向她家赶去
I had to get to her
as quickly as possible.
正要按门铃的时候...
I was going
to ring the bell...
突然我的预感告诉我 行事要万分谨慎
but then I had a hunch
I'd better be careful.
这屋子里有问题
Something was wrong
in this house.
贝基
Becky.
贝基！
Becky!
米尔斯 能告诉我到底发生了什么吗？
Miles, will you tell me
what happened?
同样的东西
The same thing.
我又找到了一具...
I found another one...
在贝基家的地下室里...
in the cellar
at Becky's house...
我站在那里盯着它的时候 它正在活转起来
coming to life
while I stood there watching it.
那是贝基
It was Becky.
是吗？我想看看这两具躯体中的任意一个
Yeah? I want to see
one of these bodies.
好的
All right.
你先上床去休息
你陪着她
You're going to bed,
and you're staying with her.
穿上外衣
我们先去看看杰克的那个
Put on your clothes.
We'll go to Jack's first.
你这有咖啡吗？
Got any coffee around here?
有
厨房里能找到
Yeah.
You'll find some in the kitchen.
他不相信我的话 贝克
He doesn't believe me, Beck.
他会相信的
He will.
有人在耍花招
Somebody's playing games!
这下麻烦了
Rough ones.
这里有一处血迹
There's a blood spot.
你们看到的东西是个被杀掉的可怜的尸体
What you saw was the body
of a murdered man.
仔细检查过了吗？
Did you examine it carefully?
是的
Yes.
我实在不知道它到底发生了什么
I don't know
what's happened to it.
那并不是一具普通的尸体
上面没有任何特征
It wasn't an ordinary body.
There wasn't a mark on it.
我也仔细检查过了
连任何蛛丝马迹都没有
I checked it, too.
Not a scratch.
有这样一种杀人手法...
You can kill a man...
用削尖的细冰椎刺入大脑的话...
by shoving an ice pick
into the base of his brain...
只会留下一个肉眼几乎看不见的微小创口
leaving a puncture so small
the naked eye can't see.
妈的 你在无视事实真相
这压根就不是一具普通的尸体
You're ignoring the fact
this wasn't a normal body.
而且你也听到泰迪提到它手上的伤口
What about the hand
Teddy mentioned?
泰迪的胡言乱语我听过太多了
全部都是扯淡
I heard lots of things
Teddy said and none made sense.
等等 伙计
当时我也在场
Hold on, pal.
I was here, too.
米尔斯也在
So was Miles.
瞧 我们提取了它的指纹
Look, we took his fingerprints.
看看这个吧
告诉我为什么它没有指纹
Look at that.
Tell me why it didn't have any.
他不喜欢留下指纹
所以用强酸洗掉了
He didn't want any,
so he took them off with acid.
别试图用常识去解释一切了
Stop trying
to rationalize everything.
我们手边的这事是个谜
We have a mystery on our hands.
是啊 的确是个谜
Sure. A real one.
到底是谁的尸体
并且它现在在哪里
Whose body was it,
and where is it now?
只不过完全是个普普通通的谜题而已
A completely normal mystery.
别管它现在在哪里
这件事绝不会超越人类的经验范围
Whatever it is, it's well within
the bounds of human experience.
而且我也不认为你们能让它超越
Don't blow things
out of proportion.
如果不是因为我在贝基家的地下室看到的东西
我才不会像现在这样
I wouldn't if I hadn't
looked in Becky's cellar.
我在那看到的躯体 你又怎么解释？
How do you explain the body
I saw there?
我不认为你看到了任何东西
I don't think you saw one.
你也不相信我在这看到的？
And the body here?
我知道你在这看到了
其他的三个人也都看到了
I know you saw it.
Three others saw it, too.
但另外一个是我梦见的还是什么？
But I dreamed up
the second one?
医生也是会产生幻觉的
Doctors can have
hallucinations, too.
人类的精神是种奇妙的存在
The mind is a strange
and wonderful thing.
甚至也许永远都不能够被完全彻底地解读
I'm not sure it'll ever be able
to figure itself out.
其它的事物或许都可以--
从原子 到宇宙--
Everything else, maybe...
from the atom to the universe...
任何事物 除了人类的精神世界
everything except itself.
不管怎么说
我看到了贝基的分身...
Nevertheless,
I saw Becky's double...
而我们在这里见到的那具躯体...
and the body that we saw here...
化成了令人不舒服的 酷似杰克的东西
bore an uncomfortable
resemblance to Jack.
极度令人不舒服
Mighty uncomfortable.
好吧 让我们去贝基家瞧瞧
Let's go to Becky's
and have a look.
好吧 你女朋友的分身在哪里？
Where's your
girlfriend's double?
好 怀疑论者
打开这个盖子
OK, skeptic,
lift the lid.
有具躯体在里面吧
对吗？
There's a body here,
all right.
- 那就是贝基的分身
- 当然是
- It's Becky's double.
- It sure is.
你再来看看
Take another look.
现在你看
你根本就没在这里看见过什么
Now you see it,
now you don't.
它之前就在那里的--
被那个毯子裹着
It was there...
half-hidden by that blanket.
你说你是刚刚才在这里看见过的
You said
you saw it there just now.
我以为我看到了
I thought I did.
今晚你为何跑到贝基家里来？
Why did you come here
tonight?
你在杰克家看到了一个死人...
You'd seen a dead man
at Jack's...
身材普通的人
an average-sized man.
死去的脸上
线条柔和没有棱角...
The face in death
was smooth and unlined...
表情空洞
这是常有的事
bland in expression,
which often happens.
你只是刚刚才开始注意到...
You had just become aware...
这一场奇怪的 无法用常识解释的
歇斯底里的流行性集体癔病
of a curious, unexplainable,
epidemic mass hysteria.
男人 女人 孩子们
突然都开始坚信...
Men, women, and children
suddenly convinced themselves...
身边的亲人不再是原本的亲人...
that their relatives weren't
their relatives at all...
所以你的意识开始欺骗你...
so your mind
started playing tricks...
现实变得不再真实
and reality became unreality.
在你眼里那个死人变成了杰克的分身
The dead man became
Jack's double in your eyes.
得了吧 好吗 丹
Come off it, Dan.
我知道这些听起来难以置信...
I know
it's all hard to believe...
但的的确确是可能发生的事情--
哪怕是我这样的巫医也不一定能躲得过
but these things happen...
even to witch doctors like me.
我在这看见她了！
千真万确！
I saw her here!
She was real!
你当然看到了 从每一个细节...
You saw her
in every tiny detail...
就像任何一个人看到
任何其它事物一样的鲜活生动...
as vividly as anyone
has ever seen anything...
但那仅存在于你的脑海中
but only in your mind.
丹尼你可以一整晚都在这里阐述理论
但你说服不了我
Danny, talk all night,
but you're not convincing me.
天啊你们在我家地下室干什么？
What are you doing in my cellar?
用来做诊室
这两位先生是病人...
Using it for an office.
These gentlemen are patients...
急需要精神科的治疗
badly in need
of psychiatric treatment.
他们一直在做噩梦
They've been having nightmares.
要是喝多了
你们最好现在醒醒酒
If you're drunk,
you'd better sober up quick.
警察正在来这里的路上
The police are coming.
不不 我们没醉
No, we're not drunk.
不是那么简单的事
拿把椅子过来
Nothing that simple.
Pull up a chair.
怎么了 你们都有毛病吧？
Why, you're all crazy.
嘿 这里发生了什么？
What's going on down there?
你好 尼克
很高兴见到你
Hello, Nick.
Glad to see you.
这两位先生不用专门再跑一趟去警局了
You saved these two characters
a trip to the station.
他们想报警 发现了一具尸体
后来它却不见了
They want to report
finding a body and losing it.
在哪儿？什么时候？
Where? When?
大概晚上7点左右在我家
At my place about 7:00.
为什么你们时隔这样久才报警？
Why did you
wait so long to report it?
你知道些什么吧 大夫？
You know better than that, doc.
呃 那时一具很诡异的躯体...
It was a curious sort
of a body...
然后 只是突然就找不到它了
and then it wasn't there
anymore.
我有个好主意 你们俩都该进局子了
I have a good mind
to throw you both in jail.
如果你看见那玩意
你就会明白为什么我们等了这么长时间
If you'd seen it,
you'd understand why we waited.
瘦小的男人...身高5英尺10英寸...
Thin man... 5'10"...
指纹被强酸抹掉了？
fingerprints burned off
with acid?
刚刚还在太平间看到它
Just seen it on the slab
in the morgue.
出现在一个燃烧的草垛旁边...
Turned up
in a burning haystack...
就两个多小时前 在迈克·加斯纳南边的牧场
on Mike Gessner's south pasture
two hours ago.
好了 散了吧！
Now break it up!
各回各家！
Go on home!
好吧 你赢了
收拾走人吧
You win.
Pick up the marbles.
早安
Good morning.
有橙汁
Orange juice.
谢谢
Thank you.
想要吃哪种蛋？
How do you
like your eggs?
你想怎么做就怎么做
Any way you'd like.
煮蛋 两分钟？
Boiled, two minutes?
两分钟？
Two minutes?
嗯哼
Mm-hmm.
好
OK.
知道吗...
You know...
昨晚把你从床上抱走挺麻烦的...
dragging you out of bed
last night was some trouble...
但是很值得
but it was worth it.
说真的 米尔斯
Seriously, Miles.
什么声音？
What was that?
是谁？
Who is it?
煤气收费员
It's the gas man.
早上好啊大夫
Morning, doc.
早上好 查理
Good morning, Charlie.
我猜我大概有点神经过敏
I guess I'm a little jittery.
睡眠不足的缘故
Not getting enough sleep.
我不会烦扰你的
I won't bother you anymore.
把计费表放在露台了
Putting a meter outside
on the patio.
好的
OK.
天啊 鸡蛋要煮过头了
The eggs will be hard-boiled.
你也会为你丈夫这样做吗？
Did you do this
for your husband?
嗯哼
Mm-hmm.
难道你妻子不会做这些么？
Didn't your wife
do this for you?
当然 她热爱烹饪
Yes. She liked to cook.
这就是我现在为何成了
单身汉的其中一个原因--
That's one of the reasons
why I'm single...
晚餐上桌时
我几乎从未露过脸
I never was there
when dinner was on the table.
所以听我的建议...
Take my advice...
最好别跟医生搞在一起
and don't get mixed up
with a doctor.
他们几乎从不在家
They're seldom at home.
如果我告诉你...
What would you say
if I told you...
我已经跟一名医生搞上了会怎样？
I was already
mixed up with a doctor?
我会说简直美好得令人难以置信
I'd say it was too good
to be true.
这种事情
时常会突如其来地发生
Things like this
can happen all of a sudden.
什么叫“突如其来”？
对于两个...
What's "all of a sudden"
about two people...
几乎已经做了一辈子密友的人
who've been friends
most of their lives?
早安
Good morning.
我想我闻到了咖啡的香味
I thought
I smelled some coffee.
为什么没喊我起床呢？
Why didn't you give me a call?
我不想把泰迪吵醒
I didn't want to wake Teddy.
哦 她早醒了 昨晚睡得很好
She's wide-awake.
Got a good sleep.
不错
Good.
不过我不认为她应该马上跟我回家
But I don't feel
she should go home right away.
介意我们多留一会吗？
Would you mind taking in
boarders for a while?
还是说你有其他别的什么安排？
Or do you have something else
in mind?
我在琢磨一些事情...
I was toying with an idea...
不过你们当然可以留下
but you can stay.
给 杰克
Here, Jack.
谢了 宝贝
我给泰迪送上去
Thank you, doll.
I'll take it to Teddy.
米尔斯 你是否帮我安排了预约...
Miles, did you make
that appointment for me...
跟你的那个精神科医生见面
with the psychiatrist?
是的 2点
Yes. 2:00.
我想不需要了
我觉得自己好蠢
I don't need him.
I feel like such a fool.
我今早一睁眼
觉得什么事都没有了
I woke up this morning,
and everything was all right.
- 你都不知道我感到有多轻松
- 是的 我明白
- You don't know my relief.
- Yes, I do.
回去给贝基打个电话告诉她这件事好吗？
她一直好担心你
Will you call Becky
and tell her? She was worried.
好的
All right.
她现在在我家
She's at your house.
在你家？为什么？
At your house? Why?
一言难尽
不过她会跟你解释的
It's a long story,
but she'll tell you about it.
贝基还在他家
Becky's still at his house.
好吧
All right.
早安啊
Good morning.
早上好 莎莉
Good morning, Sally.
快去瞧瞧谁在会客室
Take a peek at what's
in the reception room.
妈妈 为什么我们不回家呢？
Mother,
why don't we go home?
马上就回去 吉米
In a little while,
Jimmy.
他康复得很迅速嘛
He certainly made
a quick recovery.
我想我们都是这样的
I guess we all have.
但开车回家的路上...
But driving home...
我的脑海中浮现出很多无解的疑问
I had a lot of questions
and no answers.
吉米和威尔玛怎么会在一夜之间恢复常态？
How could Jimmy and Wilma
seem so normal now?
很明显我还没有为他们做任何治疗
Surely I had done nothing
to cure them.
也许他们是想让我安下心来
可是为什么呢？
Maybe they wanted me
to feel secure, but why?
好啊...
Well...
但愿你没忘了买牛排
I hope
you didn't forget the steaks.
我从不忘事
I never forget anything.
别担心他
在这方面他口碑良好
Don't worry about him.
He's completely housebroken.
我想来点马提尼  贝克
I need a martini, Beck.
洋葱还是橄榄口味？
Onion or olive?
无所谓
我只是想浇在炭上
Doesn't matter.
I want to pour it on the coals.
这玩意老是点不着
They just won't burn.
哦 马提尼可不够烈
A martini isn't dry enough.
我去帮你找些可以点火用的东西
I'll get you something
that'll start it.
这杯是给你喝的
For drinking purposes.
你的身材看起来真是凹凸有致
You're looking shipshape.
谢谢 先生
Thank you, sir.
拿来了
Here we are.
杰克！杰克！
Jack! Jack!
呕...
Ugh.
看起来像巨型豆荚！
They're like huge seedpods!
这一定就是形成我家密室里那躯体的玩意！
This must be how that
body in my closet was formed.
米尔斯 它们是哪来的？
Where are they from?
我也不知道
如果是种子或者豆荚那样的东西...
I don't know.
If they are seeds or seedpods...
它们大概一定是从什么地方的
植物上长出来的
they must grow someplace
on a plant.
并且某些人或者东西
要它们去复制人类的躯体...
And somebody or something wants
this duplication to take place.
但一旦它们完成复制的时候...
But when they're finished...
我们的躯体会发生什么？
what happens to our bodies?
我毫无头绪
I don't know.
当整个步骤完成的时候...
我们的本体可能...
When the process is complete,
probably the original...
会被毁灭或瓦解...
is destroyed or disintegrates...
不！等等！
No! Wait!
抱歉
但我可不想亲眼目睹...
Sorry,
but I take a dim view...
自己被毁灭的惨剧发生
of watching my own destruction
take place.
在它们完全生长成型之前
暂时不会有什么危险的
There isn't any danger
until they're completely formed.
昨晚在你家咱们已经见识过了
We learned that last night
at your house.
你并不会马上被统御
Your blank
didn't change right away.
在你沉睡之前都不会
Not until you fell asleep.
米尔斯 如果这种取而代之真的发生了...
Miles, when the change
does take place...
你认为会与本来的我们有什么区别吗？
do you suppose
there's any difference?
一定有
There must be.
威尔玛注意到了
小吉米也发现了
Wilma noticed it.
So did little Jimmy.
还有我
So did I.
是我父亲...
My father.
这一定是昨晚那时他在...
That must be
what he was doing...
地下室所做的事情
安置这种东西
in the cellar last night...
placing one of these.
我很遗憾
I'm sorry.
我感到有些不对劲...
但我还以为是我自己的问题...
I felt something wrong,
but I thought it was me...
因为我离开家乡太久了
because I'd been away
for so long.
一定要毁掉它们
所有的！
They must be destroyed,
all of them!
它们会变成--
每一个...
They will be...
every one of them.
我们现在必须去检查一下镇上所有的建筑...
We're going to have to search every
building
所有的房子
every house in town.
不管男女老少都得接受检查
Men, women, and children
have to be examined.
我们要开始求援了
我留在这看住它们
We've got some phoning to do. I'm going to stay
and watch them.
我陪你一起
I'm staying with you.
千万别报警！
Don't call the police!
尼克·格里维特压根就没有从...
Nick Grivett
didn't find any body...
什么燃烧的干草垛旁边发现任何尸体！
on a burning haystack!
为什么不打电话通知丹尼？没准他能帮上忙
Why don't you call
Danny? Maybe he can help.
丹尼？
Danny?
不
No.
恐怕现在再联系丹尼 也已经太迟了
I'm afraid it's too late
to call Danny, too.
那你打算怎么办？
What are you going to do?
求救
Get help.
但愿现在所发生的一切都还
仅限于在圣米拉的范围内！
I hope whatever's taking place
is confined to Santa Mira!
这里是接线员
Operator.
你好 我是本耐尔医生
这是紧急情况
This is Dr. Bennell.
This is an emergency.
我想跟洛杉矶的联邦调查局联系
I want to talk to the Federal
Bureau of Investigation in L.A.
你确定能让他们相信你的话吗？
Can you convince them?
我别无选择
I've got to.
这些东西到底是从哪儿来的？
Where did they come from?
过去的几年间发现了很多
So much has been
discovered these past few years.
一切皆有可能
Anything is possible.
也许是核辐射...
Maybe the results
of atomic radiation...
对植物或动物产生的影响...
on plant life or animal life...
或者是什么诡异的外星生物
或基因突变一类的
some weird alien organism,
a mutation of some kind.
它们为什么要取代人类
也就是我们而存在？
Why should they take the form
of people... of us?
我不知道
I don't know.
无论是什么...
Whatever it is...
不管是出于智能还是生存本能...
whatever intelligence
or instinct it is...
那玩意能支配它们所形成的人类的血肉之躯...
that can govern the forming
of human flesh and blood...
只需要微薄的空气就可以...
out of thin air is...
简直是令人难以置信地强大...
well,
it's fantastically powerful...
直接超越了人类的理解范围
不堪设想
beyond any comprehension,
malignant.
你家地下室里的那具躯体仅仅只需要...
All that body
in your cellar needed...
拥有一个意识 而且它...
was a mind, and it was...
而且当时我睡着后
它正在尝试偷取我的意识
And it was taking mine
while I was asleep.
我真希望能亲手拿干草叉把它--
I could take
that pitchfork myself, and...
与洛杉矶的联线接通了 大夫...
On your call
to Los Angeles, Doctor...
没有人接电话
they don't answer.
再试试 它们的部门全天无休！
Try again! That office
is open day and night!
如果它们已经占领了电话系统
那我们就完蛋了
If they've taken over
the phone office, we're dead.
那是我码？
Is that me?
这是紧急情况！
紧急情况！
This is an emergency!
Emergency!
听着 这里...喂？
Look, there's been... Hello?
接线员 给我换个好点的线路
Operator,
get me a better connection.
我试试 大夫
I'll try, Doctor.
没用
It's no use.
洛杉矶那边的线路全都断了
All the Los Angeles circuits
are dead.
好吧 试试萨克拉门托那边！
给我接州政府
OK, try Sacramento!
Give me the state capital.
我要跟地方上的官员联系
I want to talk to the governor.
萨克拉门托线路忙 大夫
The Sacramento
circuits are busy, Doctor.
会再回你电话
I'll call you back.
好吧
All right.
好吧 我等你电话
I'll wait for your call.
我要把电话拿出去
I'll take the phone outside.
杰克 它们已经占领了电话系统
Jack, they've got the phone.
你和姑娘们开上你的车 先跑路
You and the girls take your car
and make a run for it.
到了附近的第一个镇 赶快求助
First town you get to,
yell for help.
那你呢？
What about you?
电话很快就会响
That phone
is gonna ring soon.
如果没有人接的话
他们可能会封锁出镇的道路
If nobody answers,
they'll block the roads.
我尽力拖住他们 直到你们走远以后
I'll stall them.
然后呢
Then what?
试试能否挖出幕后黑手
Try and find out
what's in back of this.
- 我留下
- 不！
- I'm staying.
- No!
米尔斯 别让我离开你
Miles,
don't ask me to leave you.
杰克 快上路吧
Jack, get going.
米尔斯 我不能--
Miles, I can't...
总有人要先走
否则的话我们没办法搬救兵！
Somebody's got to go,
or we don't get help!
拜托 我们快离开这里吧
Please,
let's get out of here!
你们自己保重
Watch out for yourselves.
到电话那里去 在那呆着
Go over by the phone.
Stay there.
如果电话响了 喊我
If it rings, call me.
你好
Hello.
本耐尔大夫在吗？
Is Dr. Bennell there?
- 在 我去叫他
- 不要紧
- Yes. I'll get him.
- Never mind.
请转告他萨克拉门托那边
仍然线路忙就可以了...
Just tell him the Sacramento
circuits are still busy...
再问问他是否需要我继续尝试帮他转接
and ask him if he wants me
to keep trying.
好的 稍等
All right. Hold on.
米尔斯 那边还是线路忙！
Miles,
the circuits are still busy!
让她继续试！
Tell her to keep trying!
还有 再试试三藩市和华盛顿！
Also, try San Francisco
and Washington!
我们现在立即走人
We're getting
out of here right now.
去哪里？
Where are we going?
莎莉家
Sally's!
洛杉矶方面还是接不通
We're still unable
to get through to Los Angeles.
需要我继续尝试吗？
Do you wish me to keep trying?
本耐尔大夫？
Dr. Bennell?
我需要个可以信任的人...
I needed
someone I could trust...
然后我发现莎莉
我的护士 是最好的人选
and I figured Sally, my nurse,
was my best bet.
我决定试试给她打电话看看她是否在家
I decided to try to phone her
to see if she was at home.
也许公用付费电话线路还没有被占领
Maybe they hadn't
taken over the pay phones.
我试试付费电话
I'll try the pay phone.
嗨 麦克！
Hey, Mac!
哦 嗨 大夫 你好吗？
Oh, hi, doc.
How are you?
听着 可以赶快帮我加个几加仑吗？
我赶时间
Will you get me
a couple gallons fast?
当然
玛莎 大夫在赶时间
Sure.
Martha, doc's in a hurry!
你负责刷挡风玻璃 好吗？
Get the windshield, will you?
我得把钥匙拔下来去开油箱
I have to have the keys
to open the gas tank.
这条路那边有病人？
Somebody sick out this way?
那边出了事故
There's been an accident.
有意思 我们还没听到这个消息
Funny.
We haven't heard about it.
呃 刚刚才发生的事情
It just happened.
我还没来得及拨她的号码...
Before I could
even get her number...
就看见麦克靠近了我的车的后备箱
I saw Mac closing
the trunk of my car.
他或许是在帮我检查备胎情况...
He could have been
checking my spare tire...
但我不这么想
but I didn't think so.
这样就好了
That should do it.
谢谢你
Thank you.
都搞定了？
All set?
- 都搞定了 大夫
- 好的 多谢
- All set, doc.
- Fine. Thanks.
- 记我账上 好吗？
- 当然了 大夫
- Put it on my bill, will you?
- Sure, doc.
怎么了？
What's the matter?
我们得现在赶去莎莉家
We've got to make it
to Sally's house.
我不确定是否再有任何人可以信任了...
I wasn't sure
I could trust anyone...
但无论怎样 我想去莎莉那里碰碰运气
but I took a chance
and drove to Sally's anyway.
当我看到屋子前面停了很多车时...
When I saw several cars
in front of the house...
我决定谨慎点
I decided to play it safe.
有什么不对吗？
What's wrong?
也许没有 但还是先不要进去...
直到我确定那边安全为止
Probably nothing,but we're not going
in there until I'm sure it's safe.
握紧方向盘
随时准备立刻开车...
Slide under the wheel
and get out of here fast...
如果有任何人出现来抓我们的话
if anybody shows up
looking for us.
宝宝睡着了吗 莎莉？
The baby asleep yet, Sally?
还没呢
不过就快了...
Not yet,
but she will be soon...
然后就再也不会哭闹了
and there'll be no more tears.
需要我把这个放在她的房间吗？
Shall I put this in her room?
是的 放在她的围床上
Yes. In her playpen.
不 等等
也许由我来更好
No, wait.
Maybe I'd better take it.
怎么不进屋去呢 米尔斯？
Why don't you go in, Miles?
我们大家都在等你呢
We've been waiting for you.
贝基 开车！
快！
Becky, start the car!
Quick!
贝基 走！
Becky, get going!
注意 所有部队...
Attention, all units...
注意 所有部队--
准备逮捕...
attention, all units...
apprehend and detain...
米尔斯·本耐尔医生和贝基·德里斯科尔...
Dr. Miles Bennell
and Becky Driscoll...
正在向北方前进...
now believed heading north...
开着一辆黑白相间的福特...
in a black and white
Ford sedan...
车牌号2-X-3-7-7-9-6
license number 2-X-3-7-7-9-6.
所有部队准备设置路障...
All units designated
as roadblocks...
各就各位
move to your stations.
情况紧急
It is urgent.
这两个人必须被逮捕...
These two persons
must be detained...
并且绝不允许他们离开圣米拉
and not permitted
to leave Santa Mira.
重复-- 情况紧急...
Repeat... it is urgent...
准备搜寻1955年产的黑白色福特车...
Be on the lookout for a 1955
black and white Ford sedan...
车牌号2-X-3-7-7-9-6
license number 2-X-3-7-7-9-6.
试试能不能赶到我的诊室
We'll try to make it
to my office.
从前面的公路右拐
Cut into that alley
on the right.
他会回来吗？
Do you think he'll come back?
我不认为天亮之前他们会再回来搜查
I don't think they'll
check again before morning.
到那时 杰克应该已经带着援兵赶回来了
By then, Jack should be here
with help.
如果杰克没有撑过去怎么办？
What if
Jack doesn't get through?
他一定会扛住的
He's gotta get through.
来 吃两片这个
Here. Take two of these.
能帮助你保持清醒
They'll help you to stay awake.
我们整晚都绝不能闭眼
We can't close our eyes
all night.
也许一睁眼就会变成...
We may wake up changed...
某种邪恶的 非人类的东西
into something evil and inhuman.
在实践中 我见过好多人...
In my practice,
I've seen how people...
逐渐失去人性
have allowed their humanity
to drain away.
只不过 这一过程是缓慢的
而非突如其来地
Only, it happens slowly
instead of all at once.
他们似乎毫不在意
They didn't seem to mind.
那只是少数人而已 米尔斯
But just some people.
我们都一样...一点点的
All of us... a little bit.
心肠日益变硬
逐渐麻木起来
We harden our hearts
and grow callous.
只有到我们必须奋发搏斗
才能保存自己人性的时候...
Only when we have to fight
to stay human...
才能意识到它对我们来说有多么珍贵...
do we realize how precious
it is to us...
多么昂贵...
how dear...
就像你的存在对我的意义
as you are to me.
可能是杰克在找我们
Maybe that's Jack
trying to find us.
他不会笨到打来电话
He'd know better
than to use the phone.
他去哪儿了？
Where is he?
为什么他还不来呢？
Why doesn't he come?
就像每个周六的清晨一样
Just like any Saturday morning.
莱恩·珀尔曼
比尔·比特纳...
Len Pearlman, Bill Bittner...
吉姆·克拉克和他的老婆雪莉
还有孩子们...
Jim Clark and his wife Shirley
and their kids...
我一生中所相识的所有人
people I've known all my life.
几点了？
What time is it?
七点四十五
Seven forty-five.
是的 我懂
Yeah, I know.
对于喧嚣的人流来说这也有点太早了
It's too early to be so busy.
他们都在那干什么？
What are they doing here?
有答案了
There's the answer.
那些一定都是刚到镇上的外乡人
There must be strangers in town.
他们得在这儿等车
They're waiting for the bus
to come and go.
只有在十一点的时候下一班才能来
There isn't another one
through here until 11:00.
农夫们
Farmers.
格里马尔迪  皮克斯利...
Grimaldi, Pixley...
加斯纳！
Gessner!
新奥尔良市
Crescent City.
如果你在新奥尔良市有亲友 过来拿一个
If you have Crescent City
families, step to truck one.
新奥尔良市的...
Crescent City...
来第一辆车
the first truck.
红岸
Redbank.
所有在红岸有亲友的...
All with Redbank families
or contacts...
到第二辆车这里来
go to truck number two.
所有在红岸有亲友的...
All with Redbank families
or contacts...
第二辆车
truck number two.
哈文赫斯特...
Havenhurst...
第三辆车
the third truck.
哈文赫斯特--
第三辆车
Havenhurst...
the third truck.
米尔斯镇--第三辆车
Mill Town... the third truck.
春泉谷...
Valley Springs...
第三辆车
the third truck.
春泉谷 第三辆车...
Valley Springs...
先是咱们这个镇...
First our town...
然后是咱们的那些邻镇...
then all the towns around us.
像是传染性的恶疾...
It's a malignant disease...
逐渐蔓延到全国范围
spreading through
the whole country.
今天就这么多
That's all for today.
准备好明天再来
Be ready again tomorrow.
我没时间等杰克了 你呆在这里
I can't wait for Jack
any longer. Stay here.
你不是要出去吧
You're not going out there?
我必须阻止他们！
I've got to stop them!
等等！我们在这里还是安全的！
Wait! We're safe here!
他们不在
但愿咱们来得还不算太迟
They're not here.
I hope we're not too late.
杰克！谢天谢地！
Jack! Thank God!
整个镇都被这些豆荚占领了！
The whole town's been
taken over by the pods!
还没
还剩下你和贝基
Not quite.
There's still you and Becky.
米尔斯 事情其实会简单很多...
Miles, it would have
been so much easier...
如果你昨天晚上乖乖去睡觉的话
if you'd gone to sleep
last night.
放松点
我们是来帮助你的
Relax.
We're here to help you.
你懂的
You know better than that.
需要我们将它们放在哪里？
Where do you want us
to put them?
想看看它们是怎样成长的吗？
Would you like
to watch them grow?
- 不用 谢了
- 把它们放在这
- No, thanks.
- Put them in there.
没什么可怕的 我们不会伤害你
There's nothing to be afraid of.
We're not going to hurt you.
等你明白了
你会感激涕零
Once you understand,
you'll be grateful.
还记得起初我和泰迪是如何的抗拒它吗？
Remember how Teddy and I
fought against it.
我们错了
We were wrong.
你是说泰迪不再介意了？
You mean Teddy doesn't mind?
当然不了 她现在的感觉跟我如出一辙
Of course not.
She feels exactly the way I do.
放我们走！
Let us go!
如果我们出了镇子 就不会再回来了
If we leave town,
we won't come back.
我们可不能放你们走
你们是危险人物
We can't let you go.
You're dangerous to us.
别抵抗了 米尔斯
没用的
Don't fight it, Miles.
It's no use.
不久之后 你们都必须要睡觉的
Sooner or later,
you'll have to go to sleep.
我在大厅等你
I'll wait for you in the hall.
米尔斯 你和我一样是学术界人士
Miles,
you and I are scientific men.
你能明白这发生的一切有多么奇妙
You can understand the wonder
of what's happened.
仅仅设想一下
不到一个月之前...
Just think.
Less than a month ago...
圣米拉还跟其它的城镇都一样--
Santa Mira
was like any other town...
塞满了被烦恼困扰着的人们
people with nothing
but problems.
这是突然从天上掉下来了解决之道
Then out of the sky
came a solution.
这些在太空飘荡了不知多少年的种子...
Seeds drifting through space
for years...
在农夫们的田里生了根
took root in a farmer's field.
从种子里长出了豆荚...
From the seeds came pods...
能够自我繁衍...
which had the power
to reproduce themselves...
就像其他任何的生命形式一样
in the exact likeness
of any form of life.
这就是一切是如何开始的...
So that's how it began...
...天外来客
out of the sky.
你的新肉体在里面生长成形
Your new bodies
are growing in there.
他们会从每一个细胞开始统御你的器官...
They're taking you over
cell for cell...
从每一个原子
atom for atom.
没用痛苦
There's no pain.
一夜之间 在你的睡梦中...
Suddenly, while you're asleep...
它们将吸收你的意识心智和记忆...
they'll absorb your minds,
your memories...
然后你就在另外一个没有烦恼的世界重生了
and you're reborn
into an untroubled world.
千人一面的世界？
Where everyone's the same?
没错
Exactly.
真是个好世界
What a world.
我们并不是唯一幸存的人类
We're not the last humans left.
剩下的人们会摧毁你们
They'll destroy you!
等到明天 你就不会希望他们这样做了
Tomorrow,
you won't want them to.
明天你就是我们中的一员了
Tomorrow, you'll be one of us.
我爱贝基
I love Becky.
明天 我还会有同样的感情吗？
Tomorrow, will I feel the same?
压根就不需要什么爱
There's no need for love.
没有情感？
No emotion?
所以你就没有任何感情
只有生存的本能
Then you have no feelings,
only the instinct to survive.
你失去了爱或被爱的能力！
我说的对吗？
You can't love or be loved!
Am I right?
你说的就好像这很可怕一样
You say it
as if it were terrible.
相信我 一点也不可怕
你又不是没爱过
Believe me, it isn't.
You've been in love before.
不存在永恒的爱
从不
It didn't last.
It never does.
爱，欲望，野心，信仰--
Love, desire, ambition, faith...
没有这些东西 生活会变得好简单
相信我
without them, life's so simple,
believe me.
我可不这么想
I don't want any part of it.
你忘了些事 米尔斯
You're forgetting
something, Miles.
什么？
What's that?
你没有选择的余地
You have no choice.
我猜咱们没得选了
I guess we haven't any choice.
不错
Good.
我想要去爱和被爱！
I want to love and be loved!
我还想给你生孩子
I want your children.
我不想活在一个没有爱 悲伤
或者美好的世界！
I don't want a world
without love or grief or beauty.
我宁可死
I'd rather die.
不
No.
不要
Not
除非没有任何出路了
unless there's no other way.
为什么他们不能简单地给咱们打一针...
Why didn't they
give us a shot...
或者吃点安眠药什么的呢？
or a sleeping pill or something?
药品磨损人的心智
也许是这个原因
Drugs dull the mind.
Maybe that's the reason.
哦不 行不通
No. It wouldn't work.
我也许能放倒一两个
但是没把握搞定三个
I might get one or even two,
but I couldn't get three.
你忘了些什么 亲爱的--有我
You're forgetting something,
darling... me.
现在的局面并不是三对一
It isn't three against one.
而是三对二
给我把刀
It's three against two.
Give me a knife.
不行
No.
那边
There.
到桌子那里去
Go by the desk.
里面发生了什么？
What's going on in there?
米尔斯！
把门打开！
Miles!
Unlock the door!
米尔斯 开门！
Miles, open the door!
开门 米尔斯！
Open the door, Miles!
啊！
Aah!
开门！
Open the door!
噢！啊！
Oh! Aah!
哦！
Oh!
我们唯一的希望就是开上高速路了
Our only hope is
to make it to the highway.
呃 这个
That does it.
唯一的另一条出路是前门...
The only other way
is out the front door...
而且那边一定有人在看守
and there's bound
to be somebody watching.
我们得碰碰运气
We'll have to chance it.
眼神放空一点
Keep your eyes
a little wide and blank.
别表现出任何兴趣和激情
Show no interest or excitement.
好吧 萨姆 我们终于殊途同归了
Well, Sam,
we're finally with you.
他们应该会先通知我的
They were supposed
to let me know.
头儿说他会先给警察局打电话 然后喊我
The chief said he'd phone
the station, then call me.
他打过了 但是线路忙
He phoned,
but the line was busy.
他在重拨
He's calling again now.
啊！
Aah!
看车！
Watch out!
真对不起 米尔斯
I'm sorry, Miles.
我是雅纳切克
他们跑了
This is Janzek.
They got away.
打开警报
Turn the main siren on.
嘿 台阶！
Hey! Stairs!
就几步路了
It's only a few steps more.
来啊！
他们往这边跑了！
Come on!
They went this way!
他们在那上面！
They're over there!
米尔斯 我做不到
Miles, I can't.
我坚持不下去了
I can't go on.
你一定行
Yes, you can.
这是她的外衣！
他们一定在隧道里！
Here's her sweater!
They must be in the tunnel!
看 汤米
你从那边追！
Look, Tommy,
you go that way!
放弃吧！
你们逃不掉的！
Give up!
You can't get away from us!
我们不会伤害你们的
放弃吧！
We're not going to hurt you!
Give up!
他们没在隧道里
They're not in the tunnel.
好吧 大伙儿 出来吧
来
All right, everybody, outside.
Come on.
去山上搜查一下
大伙儿 走 起来
Let's check the hills.
Everybody, move.
米尔斯 我感到无法再保持清醒了
Miles,
I can't stay awake much longer.
我想他们应该都走了
I think they're all gone now.
我们必须动身了
否则的话就永远也上不了高速了
We'd better start, or we'll
never make it to the highway.
米尔斯 我从未听到过这样美好的声音
Miles, I've never heard
anything so beautiful.
那说明我们并不是唯一仅存的...
It means we're not
the only ones left...
懂得什么是爱的人类
to know what love is.
呆在这 并祈祷他们确实是人类
就像听起来的那样
Stay here, and pray
they're as human as they sound.
再见 亲爱的
Bye, darling.
这里是KCAA电台
您二十四小时无休的欢乐唱机...
This is station KCAA,
the 24-hour platter parade...
音乐电台--
the station of music...
贝基
Becky.
贝基！
Becky!
贝基？
Becky?
贝基 你在哪儿？！
Becky, where are you?!
我在这里 米尔斯
I'm here, Miles.
你没睡着吧？
You didn't go to sleep?
我好累
I'm so tired.
他们不是人
外面有很多他们的人
They weren't people.
It was more of them.
他们正在温室培育数以千计的豆荚
They're growing thousands
of pods in greenhouses.
我们必须逃跑
We've got to get away.
我精疲力尽了 米尔斯
I'm exhausted, Miles.
我做不到了
I can't make it.
不睡一觉的话 我们都做不到的
We can't make it
without sleep.
是的 我们能行
Yes, we can.
我睡着了 米尔斯
然后那个发生了
I went to sleep,
Miles, and it happened.
噢 贝基...
Oh, Becky.
他们说得对
They were right.
我不该离开你的...
I should never have left you.
别像个蠢货一样了
米尔斯 接受我们吧
Stop acting like a fool,
Miles, and accept us.
不
No.
绝不！
Never!
他在这里！
He's in here!
抓住他！抓住他！
Get him! Get him!
在我的生命中 有过很多害怕的时候...
I've been afraid
a lot of times in my life...
但我从未体会到恐惧的真正含义...
but I didn't know
the real meaning of fear...
直到当时亲吻贝基的那刻
until I had kissed Becky.
只是短暂地陷入了睡眠
然后我所深爱的女孩就...
A moment's sleep,
and the girl I loved...
变成了一心要置我于死地的异类敌人
was an inhuman enemy
bent on my destruction.
那一刻的短暂入眠
扼杀了贝基的灵魂...
That moment's sleep
was death to Becky's soul...
就像杰克和泰迪身上发生的一样...
just as it had been
for Jack and Teddy...
还有丹·考夫曼和其他所有的人
and Dan Kauffman
and all the rest.
他们的肉体现在已经了宿主...
Their bodies were now hosts...
而里面藏匿的是外星生物
某种来自宇宙的生命形式...
harboring an alien form
of life, a cosmic form...
那种为了生存
必须取代和统御所有人类存在的生命
which, to survive,
must take over every human man.
所以我就跑 一直跑...
So I ran, I ran...
就像小吉米那天一样夺命狂奔
I ran as little Jimmy
had run the other day.
我唯一的希望就是逃离圣米拉...
My only hope was to get away
from Santa Mira...
跑上高速公路...
to get to the highway...
去警告其他人这里发生了什么
to warn the others
of what was happening.
等等！
Wait!
由他去吧！
没人会相信她的话！
Let him go!
They'll never believe him.
救命！救命！
Help! Help!
等等！
Wait!
救命！救命！等等！
Help! Help! Wait!
等等！停车！
停车听我说！
Wait! Stop!
Stop and listen to me!
听我说！
Listen to me!
那些人正在追杀我 他们不是人类！
Those people that are coming
after me! They're not human!
听我说！
我们的处境非常危险！
Listen to me!
We're in danger!
走开！
Get out of here!
你们都处于险境 请听我说！
You're in danger! Please!
滚开！
走！
Get out of here!
Go on!
开车！
Get moving!
他们想要我们所有人的命！
They're after all of us!
所有人！
All of us!
听我说！
Listen to me!
圣米拉已经没有人类幸存了！
There isn't a human being
left in Santa Mira!
停车！
Stop!
靠边停 我需要援助！
Pull over! I need your help!
发生了很恐怖的事情！
Something terrible's happened!
你喝多了 从街上走开！
You're drunk!
Get out of the street!
走开！走！
Get out of here! Go on!
你疯了吗？大蠢货！
Are you crazy,
you big idiot?
看呐！
你们这些傻瓜 你们深处险境！
Look!
You fools! You're in danger!
看不见吗？
他们就在后面！
Can't you see?
They're after you!
他们想要我们所有人的命！
They're after all of us!
我们的妻女 我们的孩子
所有人！
Our wives, our children,
everyone!
他们已经来了！
They're here already!
你就是下一个！
You're next!
你是下一个！
下一个！
你一个字都不相信 是吧？
You don't believe
a word of this, do you?
当然 我知道这听起来很奇异
但是它实实在在的发生了！
Sure, it's fantastic,
but it happened.
别只是坐在那里用
正在估量拘束衣尺寸的眼神看我！
Don't just sit there
measuring me for a straitjacket!
做些什么！拿起电话！请求援助
Do something! Get on the phone!
Call for help!
唉！什么都没用！
What's the use?
你认为精神理疗会有效吗？
What do you think?
Will psychiatry help?
如果他说的这些仅仅是个噩梦的话 会的
If all this
is a nightmare, yes.
当然只是个噩梦啦
Of course it's a nightmare.
异世界来的植物取代地球上的人类
Plants from another world
taking over human beings.
像三月的野兔一样疯狂
Mad as a March hare.
这是什么情况？
What have we here?
他开着大卡车闯红灯
He ran his truck
through a red light.
被一辆灰狗长途车从侧面撞到了...
Greyhound bus
smacked him broadside...
翻了车
and tipped him over.
把他送到手术室
Put him in the O.R.
替我接管本耐尔好吗？
Will you take over Bennell
for me?
当然
Certainly.
伤得有多重？
How badly is he hurt?
双腿和左臂 全部粉碎性骨折
Both legs, left arm,
broken all to bits.
我们当时得把他...
We had to dig him out...
从一堆非常奇异
见所未见的东西下面挖出来
from under the most
peculiar things I ever saw.
什么东西？
What things?
我不知道那些事什么玩意
I don't know what they are.
我从没有见过那样的东西
I never saw them before.
看起来就像 呃...
超级巨型豆荚
They looked like, uh,
great big seedpods.
豆荚？
Seedpods?
这卡车是从哪里来的？
Where was the truck
coming from?
圣米拉
Santa Mira.
打开电台
拉响全面警报
Get on your radio
and sound an all-points alarm.
封锁高速公路 阻止所有交通...
Block all highways
and stop all traffic...
给州立的所有执法机关打电话
and call every law enforcement
agency in the state.
接线员 麻烦帮我接联邦调查局
Operator, get me the Federal
Bureau of Investigation.
是的！紧急情况！
Yes, it's an emergency!